

Karsten Held SharePoint Specialist/Trainer C#/Web Developer Freelancer & Contractor

Karsten Held Rothenburger Straße 32 D-01099 DRESDEN

+49 176 70861679

karstenheld3@gmail.com

www.karstenheld.com

Personal Profile

An enthusiastic, energetic and hard working developer who is able to design complex business solutions using Microsoft SharePoint and Office platforms. Experience in data integration and cross-platform projects using web-based APIs. Possessing extensive knowledge of fund management and trading processes. 20 years experience in designing and programming business applications with focus on usability and performance. Profound knowledge of web design and development. Top Excel expert and front-end designer. Always willing to learn new state-of-the-art frameworks and cross-platform technologies to achieve first-class modern solutions.

I'm looking for work as a freelancer/contractor in SharePoint, .NET and web application development projects from Jan 2021.

Areas of expertise

- Designing Mid- to large-scale intranet solutions using Microsoft SharePoint
- Business Automatization Solutions
- Intranet & Web development

- Office 365 Apps & Add-Ins
- SharePoint Apps/WebParts
- WinForms, WPF, XAML
- Excel Tools & Prototypes
- HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3
- iOS/Android HTML5 Apps
- Bootstrap, Angular, KO
- Bloomberg/Reuters API

Career History



SEP 2016 – NOW

Contractor: SharePoint Online Solutions, Administration, Training and C#/JS Development

- 2019 Now: SharePoint Admin, 3rd Level Support, Reporting, SharePoint Trainer for <u>Vattenfall</u>
- 2019: SharePoint Online Contact and Event Management System for GASAG, Berlin
- 2018 Backend Optimizing (ASP.NET, JS, Sencha, C#, EntityFramework, PL/SQL) for <u>Vattenfall</u>
- 2017 2018 SharePoint2013/Nintex/Excel/VBA/Outlook Solution for IT Security Self-Assessment (Dep. 192, ISSA) with Reporting and Data Import/Export for Deutsche Post AG / DPDHL, Bonn
- 2017 Backend Performance Optimizing (ASP.NET, C#, nHibernate, SQLServer) for API Automotive
- 2016 2017 SharePoint 2013 based Product Inventory System for <u>T-Systems</u> / <u>Telekom</u>, Bonn

IAN 2015 - AUG 2016

Freelancer & Contractor: SharePoint Consulting & Migrations M-Events, AUC, GEOMAGIC

- 2016 Mailbox migrations to Office 365 and fileshare migrations to SharePoint
- 2015 2016 SharePoint Consulting and Mobile App with SharePoint Backend

IAN 2013 - DEC 2014

Freelancer & Contractor: Development for Startups

- Development of <u>Excel-based Time Tracking Solution</u> for <u>WhizzyTools</u>.
- Development of <u>DesktopTracker</u> Monitoring-Tool in Java for Avalain, Budapest.

JUL 2012 - DEC 2012

Project Manager at Communardo Software GmbH, Dresden

Intranet-Solutions with SharePoint 2013 for <u>Axel Springer AG</u> and <u>Voestalpine Group</u>.

NOV 2008 - MAY 2012

Freelancer: Web Designer & Developer

■ 2008 - 2012 Web-Development and Softwaretools for <u>Bencer</u>, Shanghai and <u>Osyon Gmbh</u>, Berlin

JAN 2001 - AUG 2008

Developer, Junior Fonds-Manager, IT Project Manager bei Vescore Solutions AG

- 2006 2008 Development of central Asset Management Infrastructure (C#, VBA, Excel, Bloomberg)
- 2004 2006 Investmentfund manger (Value, Private Equity)
- 2001 2004 Development of Web-Apps and Tools (Java, Swing, C#, WinForms, SOAP)

MAR 2000 - DEC 2000

Software Developer at Dr. Grob & Partner AG, Winterthur

Design and prototyping of a bridge and tunnel management system (Visual Basic 6, ORACLE)

Education

MCP Exams

Exam 331: Core Technologies for Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013

Exam 486: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications

2013 – 2015 Exam 480: Developing ASP.NET MVC web Applications

Exam 480: Developing ASP.NET MVC web Applications

Exam 480: Programming in HTML5 with Javascript and CSS3

Exam 488: Developing Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013 Core Solutions

OCT 1994 – FEB 2000 Master of Civil Engineering (Dipl.-Ing) at <u>Bauhaus-University Weimar</u>
OCT 1997 – FEB 2000 Media Design at <u>Bauhaus-University Weimar</u> without degree.

LANGUAGES German, English, Hungarian



Karsten Held

Factsheet

C# (VisualStudio) JavaScript Java VBA

Expert
Advanced
Advanced
Expert

MS Office 365 Apps MS SharePoint Bloomberg API MS SQL Server

Expert
Expert
Advanced
Basic

Visit www.karstenheld.com for a detailed list of projects, customers and screenshots.

HTML5, CSS3, MVC4 WPF, XAML Angular, Bootstrap WinForms

Advanced	
Advanced	
Advanced	
Expert	
Expert	

Technology Experience

Programming Languages and **Environments**

- C#, VB.NET, VBA, Powershell
- Java
- JavaScript (EC6), Coffeescript
- Node.js
- Autolt, Lua, PL/SQL

Backend Technologies

- JSON
- RESTful APIs
- OData, OAuth 2.0
- CORS
- SOAP Web Services

Databases

- SQL Server 2005-2016, SQL Azure
- Oracle 10g 12g
- MySQL
- Cassandra, Firebase
- MS Access

Custom Backends & APIs

- SharePoint REST/CSOM API
- SharePoint CAML
- Dropbox REST API (V2)
- Bloomberg COM API
- Reuters COM API
- Datastream SOAP API
- Firebase REST API
- Google/Yahoo Finance REST

.NET Technologies & Concepts

- WPF4. XAML
- WCF, WWF4
- ADO.NET, Entity Framework
- ASP.NET. MVC4
- Windows Forms, Web Forms
- Generics, LINQ, Encoding
- Entity Framework, nHibernate

UI Frameworks & Web Technologies

- Microsoft MVC4 / AJAX / JQuery
- WPF/XAML, WinForms
- DOM, JQuery, AngularJS, Sencha
- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Less, Compass, HAML
- SVG, Canvas, Web Components
- Bootstrap, Foundation
- Ionic / Supersonic
- Java Swing, Vaadin

Development Tools

- Git, TFS, SVN
- Visual Studio 2017, ReSharper
- Maven, NPM, Bower
- NuGet, Chocolatey, Boxstarter
- Grunt, Gulp, JSHint
- NUnit, JUnit, Jasmine, Mocha
- ANTS, dotTrace, JProfiler
- Handlebars/Moustache
- TOAD, SQL*Plus, SQL Developer
- GenyMotion, Vagrant

SharePoint Technologies & Concepts

- SP & NINTEX Workflows
- SP REST API, PnP Framework
- SP CSOM, JSOM, SSOM
- ODATA, CAML, OAUTH
- SharePoint / PnP Powershell
- BCS, BDC, ECT, ACL
- WCM & ECM
- Azure ACS, App Security
- Remote Event Receiver
- KQL & FQL
- MMS API

Programming Concepts

- Promises, Callbacks, Events
- Modules, Closures, Hoisting
- Lambda Expressions

Cryptography

- AES256, PBKDF2
- SHA256, HMAC
- Crypto.JS
- .NET/JAVA Cryptography

Quality Management

- SCRUM, JIRA, Youtrack
- ITIL, ISO 9001

Content Management Systems

DotNetNuke, Ghost, Joomla

Services



Application Development

Application design, prototyping and programming using C#, JavaScript, WPF/XAML and WinForms. Office 365 Apps in the cloud (Office365 App Model) or local Office Solutions using VSTO/COM Add-Ins or VBA.



SharePoint Solutions

Design, configuration and rollout of SharePoint solutions. WebPart and App Development in C# and JavaScript. Integration with other LOB solutions. Upgrading of MS Access and ASP.NET solutions.



Mobile Development

Mobile Business Apps for iOS and Android using the AppGyver Framework with HTML5/JS/Cordova under the hood. Apps are downloaded via a scanned QR code or can be published to the official App Stores.



Web Design & Development

Responsive websites using HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, ASP.NET, MVC4, JQuery and frameworks (Bootstrap, Foundation, Ember, Knockout, AngularJS). Complete Web-Design.